<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>what's the point</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/linux.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2013-07-03T18:06:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Why ditch Windows</title><link href="/why-ditch-windows.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-03T18:06:00-03:00</updated><author><name>hernantz</name></author><id>tag:,2013-07-03:why-ditch-windows.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I won't give reasons to you to ditch Windows, but rather my answer to 
the OS switching dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream OSes (OS X, windows and ubuntu) can provide a great or an awful 
experience, give you headaches and bring you satisfactions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not what features each OS has, but what is your willingness to solve 
the problems you will likely find in your way. 
An this applies exactly for almost anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the university, we got ubuntu in the library's PCs. A friend of mine wanted 
to open a pdf file in those and for some x reason he couldn't. He told me: 
"What!....is this linux? Linux sucks, I can't even open a pdf file!" 
I'm pretty sure his conclusions would have been different if the same experience 
had happened in his Windows 7 notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are not rationale when making decitions. Some people don't care if apps are open-source or not, 
they want them to just work, or sometimes they want to be on fashion becouse 
everyone is using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even some people can live and think in three parallel dimensions, which allows 
them to love the open source philosophy, use windows and want to have a mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let him decide. Better than giving reasons for using or not using &lt;insert OS here&gt;, 
I would just say: "Switch if you want, and use it on your own risk, as I did"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I switched to Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>