<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>what's the point</title><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://hernantz.github.io/</id><updated>2015-08-09T00:00:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Some reviews</title><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/some-reviews.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-08-09T00:00:00-03:00</updated><author><name>hernantz</name></author><id>tag:hernantz.github.io,2015-08-09:some-reviews.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I plan to be reviewing books, series, albums, games, bands and movies. I'm no
expert in any of these, It's just that I want to put my impressions on ink (or
pixels I should say). These reviews are a subset of what I had consumed over
time. The order in which these reviews appear is not necessarily the order in
which I consumed those things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: Expect spoilers, all ye who enter here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It Follows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3235888/" title="It follows"&gt;&lt;img alt="It follows" src="/images/it-follows.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a sexually-transmitted curse is very original, plus the soundtrack
and the 80'ish atmosphere makes it not the the average horror movie that
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zz6KOsePEHs"&gt;Hollywood has us used to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, there are many mistakes in the plot. Some basic unanswered
questions that are: Why didn't they go to school? where are their parents? how
did the ex-boyfriend know so much about the curse? why did the ex-boyfriend do
that stupid "kidnapping"?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would have been better if this group of friends discovered more and more
about the curse by accident, like relating the moment when Jay started seen
&lt;em&gt;the thing&lt;/em&gt; (her sexual encounter with her boyfriend) with an infidelity of her
boyfriend. That way they would have learned how the curse operates and is
passed around. The plan to get rid of it could have consisted on passing the
curse to someone undesirable, like one of the bullies from school.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 3.3/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Wonderful Wizard of Oz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/236093.The_Wonderful_Wizard_of_Oz" title="The Wonderful Wizard of Oz"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Wonderful Wizard of Oz" src="/images/the-wonderful-wizard-of-oz.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being a childish fantasy book, the weird characters have thoughts are
susceptible of a more mature interpretation. I found it somehow entertaining and
relevant, I would say that this book can be enjoyed no matter the age or time.
That's what makes it a classic I think. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 4/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eyes wide shut&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120663/" title="Eyes wide shut"&gt;&lt;img alt="Eyes wide shut" src="/images/eyes-wide-shut.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scenes with the russian guy and his daughter are bizarre and stupid, I
would have skipped that entirely. Also, the part where Mr Bill is being followed
on the street, wasn't very convincing either. A threatening letter sent by the
mysterious guys to Mr Bill's house, would've been more appropriate. But aside
from that, the movie is incredibly well done (and realistic in it's own way).
It all about the idea of having an adventure, the constant struggle of a normal
couple to keep the marriage vows, which seem so unnatural in this modern era,
and how that adventure ended up becoming a nightmare. I bought it.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 4.6/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mad Max: Fury Road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1392190/" title="Mad max"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mad Max: Fury Road" src="/images/mad-max.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm ok with the idea of doing a pure action, dialog-free movie. But even that
extreme action has to make sense. 
The movie has three parts: &lt;em&gt;the escape, the return and the ending&lt;/em&gt;.
The first 30 minutes are great, the atmosphere, the cars, the costumes, the
sand storm, the pursuit, the action. Then comes the return, and the movie
faints till the end showing more of the same, only this time the cars, costumes,
pursuit and action don't make any sense. And finally comes the end, which to put
it short, it simply a crap. Score should be less, but since the &lt;strong&gt;flame
guitarist was so awesome&lt;/strong&gt;, it gets a 3. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 3/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ex Machina&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0470752/" title="Ex Machina"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ex Machina" src="/images/ex-machina.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice movie. I'm not sure about how realistic is the eccentricity of the CEO. I
would have ended the movie with the helicopter arriving, and let you imagine
what could have happened. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 4/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chappie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1823672/" title="Chappie"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chappie" src="/images/chappie.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no way this movie tries to be realistic/serious, and that is why I forgive
it all the mistakes I would not forgive to any other movie. If you wanted to
watch a movie about the philosophical implications of introducing AI in our
lives, go watch "I'm robot" or "Ex-machina". This movie narrates a tale throw
different events and dialogs that converge to an epic ending. An that's it. Well
chosen characters. Excellent idea of including Die Artwoord on the movie. I
would have ended the movie, when they were buryng Yolandi. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 4.6/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting things done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1633.Getting_Things_Done" title="Getting Things Done"&gt;&lt;img alt="Getting things done" src="/images/getting-things-done.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very bad book. I couldn't read pass the second chapter. This is one of those
books that tells you the obvious, like "you need to organize yourself", and all
in a very verbose way to fill lots of pages instead of being concise. You won't
get too much out of this book other than the obvious. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 2/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A storm of swords&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/62291.A_Storm_of_Swords" title="A Storm Of Swords"&gt;&lt;img alt="A storm of swords" src="/images/a-storm-of-swords.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the whole book. There are one main concern I had when I
finished it was that Daenerys got too much power too easy. I would have made
her rise to power a combination of: her beauty, Sir Jorah's wisdom, her dragons
(with their meaning to common folks) and her populism. I'm still unsure what to
think about Tyron's luck, Lysa's death and Catelyn's resurrection.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 4.3/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team America: World Police&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372588/" title="Team America"&gt;&lt;img alt="Team America" src="/images/team-america.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very funny movie that demonstrates that (the real) America might want to free
the world, but &lt;em&gt;freedom is not free&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 4.6/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cannibal Holocaust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078935/" title="Cannibal Holocaust"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cannibal Holocaust" src="/images/cannibal-holocaust.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gore/horror movie from the 80's. The quid of the plot is that despite the
progress of our modern society, mankind still behaves in inhuman and primitive
ways. At first you feel despise for the cannibals but then you end up hating
the white guys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's real intention wasn't to be scary, but to be shocking, and while watching
it, I felt like it's gotten old, and as if it's lost that effect. This is why
it doesn't get a higher score, but still, it might be worth watching it if you
enjoy strange movies from the 80's. It's interesting to see that The Bleir
Witch Project was not original at all. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Score: 2.4/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="reviews"></category><category term="rants"></category><category term="ideas"></category></entry><entry><title>Init</title><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/init.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-03T18:06:00-03:00</updated><author><name>hernantz</name></author><id>tag:hernantz.github.io,2013-07-03:init.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my not-sexy static new blog. It starts with a single post and a single
blog. I hope this is not one of those things I start and abandon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why now? Becouse in the last weeks I felt the urge to write for myself. 
Knowing my thoughts will be publicly available forces me to think wisely, 
and arrive to better conclusions. 
Aditionally, until now didn't like any of the blogging platforms out there, 
but now with pelican, being able to craft my own posts with markdown and vim
is also part of the motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I do my best to get to the point. Quality over quantity.
Why write a thousand words if a picture says more than a thousand words?
Why write six paragraphs if you can fit an introduction, main idea
and conclusion in just three?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is short, &lt;a href="http://getnashty.com/write-less"&gt;write less&lt;/a&gt;, read this and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Sorry for the length of this post. I didn't have time to make it shorter.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="ideas"></category></entry></feed>