<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>what's the point</title><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/feeds/startups.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://hernantz.github.io/</id><updated>2015-04-27T19:53:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Air, the next big thing</title><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/air-the-next-big-thing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-27T19:53:00-03:00</updated><author><name>hernantz</name></author><id>tag:hernantz.github.io,2015-04-27:air-the-next-big-thing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is wrong with startups today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack is &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/10/31/one-year-old-business-software-maker-slack-valued-at-1-12-billion/"&gt;valuated at $1.12b&lt;/a&gt;.
While freenode hosts ~55846 chat rooms and ~89238 users, or even when
&lt;a href="http://getkaiwa.com/"&gt;this kind of software&lt;/a&gt; is available for free and you can move your 
entire team there, as you did when you moved to Slack.
It's not like Twitter or Youtube where you have a comunity around the
service and it's kind of unlikely there would be a massive migration to
other service.
In Slack, the number of users doesn't matter, because is a team
communication tool, and as soon as the team decides to move elsewhere,
Slack is dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give you another example. Docker, &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-04-14/docker-said-to-join-1-billion-valuation-club-with-new-funding"&gt;said to be valuated at $1b&lt;/a&gt;. 
Provides an open source tool on top other open source tool, which 
aparently &lt;a href="http://chimeracoder.github.io/docker-without-docker/#1"&gt;is not even needed now&lt;/a&gt;, thanks to the systemd guys.
Even if Docker tries to provide a web platform, similar to what GitHub 
does for git, does that really justifies $1b valuation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen I'm here to sell you air.
A product everyone needs. We currently have 7 billion active users and
growing. Nobody is paying for it yet, but this userbase's got to worth
something, plus we have no competitors.
Sign up now on our &lt;a href="http://everyfuckingwebsite.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and connect with your friends!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="startups"></category></entry><entry><title>An MVP is not a product, it's an MVP</title><link href="http://hernantz.github.io/an-mvp-is-not-a-product-its-an-mvp.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-09T12:03:00-03:00</updated><author><name>hernantz</name></author><id>tag:hernantz.github.io,2013-11-09:an-mvp-is-not-a-product-its-an-mvp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Minimum Viable Product, or even better Minimum Viable Prototype (MVP from now on),
is a technique born in the Lean Startup movement to reduce the risk of gaining validated
learning, without spending too much effort, money and time in the wrong project direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You build a MVP to validate an idea, be it for a brand new product or a new feature 
in an existing one. 
In this stage of the project you don't care about: tests, QA, copy-pasting code, 
mocking the UI, security, code reviews, maintainability, scalability, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case this prototype is successfull, you should go and build the product or the feature to 
capitalize that validated learning, but this time, following industries best practices, 
so it can be used in production by your (paying?) users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last step is crucial. There will be the tempatation of not taking it.
The consequences of not doing it are well known, that's why we have best practices afterall.
The risk is low now. Money, time and effort won't be wasted. There is no excuse. 
An MVP is not a product, it's an MVP.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="startups"></category></entry></feed>